<opt>
  <Assistant Principal Surveyor id="1500315" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is seeking Assistant Principal Surveyor to:
 Schedule, monitor and supervise surveyors in the port including reviewing and processing of their reports and associated invoices, under the direction of the Principal Surveyor. Make recommendations for short- and long-term manpower needs based on the projected business climate in order to ensure that qualified, trained survey staffs are available as needs arise. Assign survey staff to projects based on their individual strengths and abilities, as directed by the Principal Surveyor. Evaluate the performance and development potential of direct subordinates, as directed by the Principal Surveyor. Act as Account Manager for the ABS organization regarding the application of rules, regulations, requirements, concepts, principles and processes. Implement experience and technical knowledge achieved from the ABS Survey environment by applying ABS classification principles related to the area of specialization. Assist with planning, scheduling and coordinating various phases of survey work. Monitor all work and projects performed by subordinate surveyors to ensure maintenance of quality, content, consistency and continuity. Promote the services and capabilities of ABS to present to potential customers. Implement knowledge of marine surveying to ensure that the financial aspects of approved business plans and budgets are maintained accordingly in each assigned area of responsibility. Promote participation, teamwork and the exercise of individual leadership among jurisdictional employees towards the continuous improvement of quality in all aspects of the ABS organization. Use specialized knowledge of ABS Classification Rules, guides, statutory regulations and related instructions, as well as the ABS Employee Safety Policy.
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Acquisition Support Specialist (Portfolio Planning) id="1500310" description="Description
    This role will provide acquisition program portfolio strategic planning support as part of a multi-disciplinary team performing portfolio management across multiple simultaneous programs in various stages of the acquisition process, from concept to technology transition to end user organizational components and organizations at the state, local and regional levels.
  Support Functions:
Perform high level budget analysis of current and planned program funding requirements and provide decision support and recommendations to program investment prioritization efforts.
Conduct Intra-Agency stakeholder coordination to define capability-based portfolio management requirements and incorporate into out-year budget planning documentation.
Review and provide inputs into program acquisition and budget documents across the portfolio including Acquisition Plans, Acquisition Program Baseline, Integrated Master Plan/Schedule, Congressional justifications, OMB Exhibit 300s, and Resource Allocation Plans (RAP).
Monitor individual program Integrated Master Schedules (IMS) and financial execution to ensure alignment with the baseline; assess impacts of any deviations and develop recommend courses of action.
Draft and contribute to high visibility strategic communications including responses to requests for information and/or decision briefs provided to key personnel within the Executive Branch, Congress, Agency, and Inter-Agency partners.
            " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Systems Engineer (Acquisition Program Support) id="1500311" description="Description
  This role will provide technical program management support in the acquisition, development, testing and deployment of enhanced and next generation sensor/detection systems. The position requires comprehensive knowledge of government acquisition and systems engineering process frameworks and experience contributing to the development of key systems engineering life cycle (SELC) artifacts. 
  Support Functions:
Review and provide technical inputs into key engineering documentation such as Concept of Operations (CONOPS), Operational Requirements Documents (ORD), system specifications, software interface documents, test plans and reports, technology transition plans and agreements, and sustainment plans.
Provide technical inputs into program acquisition and budget documents including Acquisition Plans, Acquisition Program Baseline, Integrated Master Plan/Schedule, Congressional justifications, and OMB Exhibit 300s.
Monitor and track status of Prime Contractors cost, schedule and technical performance. Review and evaluate prime contractors monthly cost and schedule progress reports against; identify issues and provide status provide status of action items to the government Program Manager. 
Review deliverables submitted by system development contractors to ensure compliance with specified requirements and for technical correctness; coordinate comment resolution and develop draft deliverable disposition letters as required.
Prepare material for and attend key program reviews including, but not limited to design reviews, technical interchange meetings, and Integrated Product Team (IPT)/Working Groups (WG).
Serve as a liaison between the Program Office, National Labs, system development contractors, end users, and other internal/external stakeholders to ensure central coordination of all efforts related to the planning, acquisition, development, test &amp; evaluation, delivery, installation and deployment of systems/equipment.
Contribute to high visibility program office products such as GAO/congressional inquiries, acquisition milestone briefings, and executive-level program status briefings. 
Maintain an electronic and/or hard copy repository of all program documentation and communications.
            " location="United States of America-Texas-Houston" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Surveyor II id="1500248" description="Description
 Job Description:          American Bureau of Shipping (ABS) is seeking a Surveyor II to:
  Examine and report on vessels and other marine structures during and after construction relative to compliance with the applicable requirements for classification with ABS, and meeting associated statutory and special service requirements related to Safety of Life at Sea, Loadline, Tonnage, Cargo Gear, and Pollution Prevention certification. Responsible for the administration of office procedures and monitoring of business performance at an assigned port. Provide assistance with maintaining files in an orderly and up-to-date manner. Work directly with clients to identify and resolve problems in an area of technical expertise. Prepare technically accurate and timely survey reports, and responses to letters, faxes, and other forms of communication. Perform work that involves conventional surveying practices, but may include moderately complex problem resolution and coordination of activities among other disciplines. Make visits to vessels, marine structures, and manufacturers for routine survey activities. Read engineering plans and implement knowledge of shipbuilding and vessel operations. Perform surveys in the prescribed format. Analyze problems and propose solutions.
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Engineer, SED Structures &amp; Statutes id="1500312" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping (ABS) is seeking an Engineer, SED Structures &amp; Statutes to:
  Review steel and other metallurgical industries technical inquiries, process methodologies, production techniques, quality system procedures, and material/product properties in accordance with ABS Rules. Provide advice and guidance to ABS Engineering and Surveyor staff, and to the clients in the fields of metallurgy, corrosion, and NDT, and ABS Rule interpretations. Propose new approaches to solve engineering problems encountered and add value to the engineering designs by making recommendations in terms of selection, processing, testing, and qualifying materials. Participate in ABS rule and process development, material failure investigations, technical training, seminars, and new material data-base system development. Must have knowledge of material selection, manufacturing methods, production parameters, procedures and inspection related technical activities. Must have knowledge of material substitutions, failure investigation, welding, corrosion, and coating technology. Must be able to apply knowledge of national/international standards and specifications such as ASTM, API, NACE, and IACS.
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <IT Security Engineer id="1500299" description="Description
      This role will assist in the implementation of the enterprise Risk Management Framework and ensure information system-related security risks are managed consistent with organizational business and mission objectives and the overall risk strategy. It requires candidates to have a comprehensive knowledge of IS security regulatory requirements and standards including NIST Special Publication 800 series, Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS), and other relevant standards.
      Support Functions:
  Coordinate and implement conformant IS security policies processes, procedures, and security control techniques.
Participate in risk assessments to periodically evaluate sensitivity of the system, risks, and mitigation strategies.
Ensure that information security requirements, including necessary security controls, are effectively integrated into the enterprise architecture.
Monitor and report on IS security incidents in accordance with established procedures.
Conduct vulnerability assessments and security test and evaluation.
Review system-level concepts and requirements documentation to ensure system security requirements, including certification and accreditation (C&amp;A), are incorporated.
Review and/or assist in the development of system security classification guides.
Review and administer security-related and/or export control contracts and programs with external government and/or business entities, as appropriate.
Assist in the development and presentation of IS security awareness and training.
        " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Junior IT System Administrator id="1500297" description="Description
    This role providing provides Windows system administration and basic network security and maintenance support for the Chief Information Officer (CIO).  Assists in maintaining and expanding the network infrastructure of a mission critical system.
      Support Functions:
  Maintain group policy and security settings, system authorization access request records, and the Active Directory.
Troubleshoot and quickly resolve reported issues with defective hardware, applications and software.
Deploy operating system updates, software patches and hardware or other network infrastructure upgrades.
Issue and maintain updated inventory logs of all equipment including computers, external hard drives, projectors and other peripherals.
Assist in the development and implementation of Standard Operating Procedures (SOP).
    " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Junior Operations Research Analyst id="1500296" description="Description
    This role will support operations research, data and requirements gathering, data management and analysis, and technical report development. 
  Support Functions 
Assist in the development of analytic studies and products including, but not limited to, gap analyses, operational requirements documentation, system performance metrics and assessments, trade-off studies, and cost-benefit analyses.
Facilitate large and diverse groups of stakeholders (e.g., law enforcement, intelligence, technical, policy, and federal/state/local authorities) to inform the development of analytical products.
Provide recommendations on, and technical assessments of, homeland security technologies and applications within the aviation, terrestrial, and maritime operational environments.
Present technical findings and recommendations to senior government management and non-technical audiences.
Attend Integrated Product Team (IPT) meetings, Working Groups (WG), technical interchange meetings, workshops, conferences, and in-process reviews as directed.
    " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <IT Program Manager id="1500301" description="Description
    This role will be responsible for coordinating, managing and providing oversight of Capital Planning and Investment Control (CPIC) activities and conducting business process analyses, needs assessments, and preliminary cost/benefits analyses in order to align information technology solutions. The successful candidate shall have demonstrated experience serving in an IT Portfolio Management position and leading complex IT projects from planning through deployment.
  Support Functions:
Coordinate and contribute to the development of OMB Exhibit 300, Exhibit 53, Resource Allocation Plans, and other CPIC artifacts.
Respond to financial reporting requirements regarding cost performance metrics, IT infrastructure costs and working capital fund cost and contributions.
Develop and implement relevant IT policies and procedures, including those for architecture, standards, purchasing, and service provision.
Formulate requirements and documentation requisites in support of infrastructure, projects and standardized processes.
Provide evaluation and audit support services, to include analysis of alternatives, cost benefit analysis, risk management, performance management, acquisition management and operational analysis
    " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Strategic Planner id="1500305" description="Description
  This role performs the end-to-end test planning, execution and analysis/reporting process for Commercial Off the Shelf (COTS) and advanced sensor/detection technologies at various stages of the Systems Engineering Life Cycle (SELC) and may include Developmental Testing, Operational T&amp;E, Advanced Technology Demonstrations and Pilot Programs. 
  Support Functions
Assists with strategic T&amp;E planning, resource planning, coordination, test program execution, and formal reporting.
Review and contribute to key acquisition program technical documentation including, but not limited to, Test &amp; Evaluation Master Plans (TEMP), System Verification plans, Test Campaign Plans, Data Collection and Validation Plans, Milestone Briefings, System Evaluation Reports, Operational Utility Assessments, Final Test Reports, etc. 
Provide T&amp;E technical advisory support to multi-disciplinary Integrated Product Teams/Working Groups.
Support the execution of discrete performance test/operational test/data collection events and conduct objective analysis of the collected system/integrated systems’ performance data.
Develop T&amp;E-related inputs into high visibility and/or executive-level reports and briefings, program reviews, and status reports.
Provide analysis of test processes and procedures and make recommendations for improving test processes to facilitate timely capability delivery to users.
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <SharePoint Administrator id="1500304" description="Description
  This role requires the capability to perform data management, analysis and administrative functions to enhance and maintain an enterprise-level SharePoint platform used to share information and collaborate across a broad stakeholder community. 
  Support Functions:
Work closely with stakeholders to elicit and validate user requirements to develop custom workflows, pages, and list views, and implement scripts as necessary to achieve the user requirements.
Review/set up access control structures based on identified user categories and assist in the development of user access request procedures.
Create and manage documents and the records management architecture and content databases.
Assist in the development and implementation of policies, processes and tools to meet compliance, information protection, and mission requirements.
Assist in the development of data management policy/processes for products developed using the SharePoint platform.
Conduct a capability gap assessment of existing information sharing and collaboration tools and establish a prioritized list of requirements.
Conduct user training for all levels of usage and administration.
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Junior Technical Writer id="1500306" description="Description
  This role will assist in the development and finalization of key acquisition program technical documentation including, but not limited to, Test &amp; Evaluation Master Plans (TEMP), System Verification plans, Test Campaign Plans, Data Collection and Validation Plans, System Evaluation Reports, Operational Utility Assessments, Final Test Reports, internal policy and procedure documents, and both internal and external briefings. The successful candidate will possess exceptional oral and written communications skills and have superior proficiency with Microsoft Office Programs.
  Support Functions
Review draft and near-final engineering and technical documents and propose text changes to document sections to enhance consistency, readability, clarity, and understanding. 
Participate in the development and drafting of senior level and high visibility presentations.  Provide support for the review and finalization of “high-impact” presentations, discussions, and project summaries.
Perform technical reviews of other systems engineering deliverables and products and make recommendations for product improvement or process enhancement.
Implement disciplined document control procedures, in accordance with defined policies and procedures, throughout the iterative review process.
Format documentation into pre-approved templates
Consolidate reviewer comments, assist in adjudication comments, document rationale for acceptance/rejection of recommendations, and incorporate final approved changes into the document or briefing.
Produce final documents and assist in coordinating the final approver(s) signatory process.
    " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Mid-Level Operations Research Analyst id="1500295" description="Description
    This role will support operations research, data and requirements gathering, data management and analysis, and technical report development.
  Support Functions
Assist in the development of analytic studies and products including, but not limited to, gap analyses, operational requirements documentation, system performance metrics and assessments, trade-off studies, and cost-benefit analyses.
Facilitate large and diverse groups of stakeholders (e.g., law enforcement, intelligence, technical, policy, and federal/state/local authorities) to inform the development of analytic products.
Provide recommendations on, and technical assessments of, homeland security technologies and applications within the aviation, terrestrial, and maritime operational environments.
Present technical findings and recommendations to senior government management and non-technical audiences.
Attend Integrated Product Team (IPT) meetings, Working Groups (WG), technical interchange meetings, workshops, conferences, and in-process reviews as directed.
      " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Program Analyst (Stakeholder Engagement) id="1500307" description="Description
  This role will support the overall planning, execution, coordination, and programmatic support for complex stakeholder outreach and operational capability development efforts.
Support Functions:
In close cooperation with FSLT&amp;T stakeholders, develop overall program strategy, policy, concepts of operations (CONOPS) and standard operating procedures (SOPs) as well as the other processes, procedures, and documents needed to establish viable and sustainable programs.
Assist in establishing and coordinating Programs in each of the 50 states and identified regions and provide oversight of program development and sustainment efforts to include training and exercise support.
Provide planning support for travel, meeting coordination, and other administrative functions as required
Track the preparation of reports and documentation to ensure they meet suspense timelines.
Schedule and coordinate the planning and execution of program meetings, reviews and other events as required.  
Assist in the development of briefings, white papers, executive summaries; attend meetings and perform other tasks as assigned.
        " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Homeland Security Analyst (Maritime) id="1500287" description="Description
    This role will assist in the performing front-end analysis of complex architectures to identify operational and technical gaps within the maritime mission area.
     Support Functions
  Perform key liaison duties with the user community to determine user requirements for systems and components
 Conduct capabilities-based planning and analysis to identify technology and operational gaps, define associated vulnerabilities and assist in developing future requirements. 
 Facilitate large and diverse groups of stakeholders (e.g., law enforcement, intelligence, technical, policy, and federal/state/local authorities) to identify operational requirements and inform the development of analytic products.
 Review and provide technical inputs into key engineering documentation including Concept of Operations (CONOPS), gap analyses, cost-benefit analyses, trade studies, Operational Requirements Documents (ORD), and other high level systems architecture documentation.
 Evaluate ongoing and planned initiatives across the organization and develop strategic and implementation plans to prioritize efforts and provide programmatic support to current projects.
 Provide programmatic support including budget guidance, project plan development, schedules/milestone tracking, and deliverable requirements.
 Assist in the development and implementation of operational support programs and procedures using a disciplined solutions development process
    " location="United States of America-Texas-Houston" schedule="Full-time" />
  <HR Representative id="1500302" description="Description
 General Summary
This position is an entry-level/junior role. In this position, the incumbent will manage the onboarding process for all new hires in North America within our applicant tracking system as well as provide basic HR assistance to assigned business units. In addition, this person will gain exposure to various areas within HR as they serve as a liaison between the HR Team and other adjacent areas such as training and development, compensation, and corporate communications.
  Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
Provide HR assistance to assigned business units.
Manage onboarding administration via Taleo applicant tracking system.
Works with various HR departments such as training and development, recruiting, and compensation to implement various deliverable for ABS Group.
Resolves employee issues including payroll, benefits and technology items
Works with more senior HR personnel to help resolve a wide variety of employment issues including investigations, performance issues and policy clarification.
Assists HR Assistant with new hire orientation activities.
Creates or revises HR policies and procedures.
Serves as a backup for HR Assistant.
Delivers training on various HR initiatives and programs.
 " location="United States of America-Texas-Houston" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Senior Manager, IT Security id="1500277" description="Description
 Responsible for maintaining and building the corporate-wide information security program to ensure that information assets are adequately protected and available. Principal duties include monitoring, implementation, and where necessary, development of departmental security practices designed to satisfy customer specifications and expectations regarding IMS services and products developed or installed.

This is a senior level management position requiring a minimum of ten (10) years previous related work experience to include security engineering or architecture work; project management responsibility for successful large-scale (two to three work year level of effort) projects; and prior leadership and administrative responsibility for five to ten professionals. The position requires experience working in organizations that support services provided to internal/external clients, as well as substantial experience with financial analysis, budgeting, and reporting for capital projects and operations expenses.

Principal Duties and Responsibilities

• Works with the Director and security staff to provide information security advice to IMS Vice President, IMS Directors, managers and staff, and, as necessary, to end-user management and user community.
• Develops, implements and monitors enterprise information security and risk management program to ensure the integrity, confidentiality and availability of information owned, controlled or processed by the organization.
• Oversees incident response planning as well as the investigation of security breaches.
• Works with outside consultants as appropriate for independent security audits.
• Responsible for ensuring acquisition projects and programs, and procured services and products are in compliance with all departmental and company security standards.
• Meets and confers with all levels of ABS management to report effectiveness of security controls and measures; monitor customer satisfaction with IMS services/products; and ensure that necessary system improvements and expansion projects are identified, prioritized, staffed and scheduled to meet company needs and objectives.
• Ensures the development, ongoing testing, and stewardship of the Corporate Disaster Recovery Plan; oversees implementation of plan in emergency situations.
• Reviews results of quality assurance audits, customer satisfactions surveys, customer contacts and complaints. Reports findings to Director and to IMS Vice President, ensuring corrective action plans are developed for timely resolution.
• Communicates major status of projects, personnel, customer concerns, etc. to IMS Vice President.
• Prepares and delivers both high-level and detailed presentations to ABS management and user groups.
• Is prepared to act as stand-in for the Director in his absence, and possibly for IMS Vice President, or as otherwise required to address security, technology and IT issues in any enterprise venue.
• Responsible for creating and obtaining upper management approval of detailed plans and operating budgets associated with both projects and the on-going operation of the department.
 " location="United States of America-New Jersey-Hackensack" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Business Development Manager id="1500284" description="Description
 The Business Development Manager is responsible for generating sales and growth initiatives within a territory / region of ABS Quality Evaluations Inc. This is a natural growth position for anybody seeking more senior roles in the Company.
  Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
Main objective is to sell ABS Quality Evaluation ISO Management Systems services using the strength of local affiliates business structure.
Define and maintain target lists of prospect clients for accounts to be targeted in region. Client prospecting in target region.
Develop a sales strategy for region to achieve defined sales targets.
Provides sales forecast data as well as other market and customer information for use in sales planning.
Stays within expense budgets, and observe Company sales policies.
Produce local proposals for clients / prospects in accordance with ABS QE procedures and pricing guidelines.
Actively follow up on all proposals and conduct client presentations where required. 
Provides support to operations as necessary to ensure customers are receiving appropriate service.
Assists in collections as necessary.
Communicates regularly, with Director of Business Development or Country Manager regarding opportunities, challenges and any other business matters.
Participates in special projects and teams as necessary to support the overall development of the business.
Meets or exceeds delegated sales targets.
 " location="United States of America-Tennessee-Knoxville" schedule="Full-time" />
  <NERC Cyber Security Consultant id="1500269" description="Description
 General Summary

The NERC Consultant will partner with customers and other ABSG consultants to solve a variety of challenges in the Electric Sector.
  Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
·         Identify and recommend solutions for clients in the electric sector.
·         Lead and facilitate meetings with clients and internal ABS Consulting project teams
·         Develop and facilitate training on regulatory framework and energy reliability standards.
·         Write reports and proposals
·         Performs other departmental tasks and/or participates in various projects as assigned.
 " location="United States of America-South Carolina-Charleston" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Maritime Law Enforcement Boarding Officer Instructor id="1500270" description="Description
 General Summary
  Responsible for development and delivery of Maritime Law Enforcement training courses as directed by the Regional Manager within the defined territory.  In addition, he/she will be delivering marine consulting services related to his/her background and experience.  Part of his/her activities will be assessment of marine client needs.
  Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
  This position is responsible and accountable for the following aspects:
Assesses client/market needs within assigned territory in order to effectively determine appropriate course content and design.
a.     Determines the needs of builders and owners in the ship and offshore industries.
b.    Conducts marketing activities as appropriate to solicit business.
c.     Liaisons with other personnel and management for support and advice.
d.    Deals with client enquiries, i.e. communications, agenda development, proposals writing and contracting.
e.     Liaisons with owners and builders to support development of new projects.
Monitors and prepares for effective delivery of courses.  Implements improvements where needed.
a.     May attend training as appropriate in order to develop skills for deliverly of ABS Academy courses addressing core client interests.
b.    Responsible for ensuring all course materials are prepared in advance for each course ready for delivery
c.     Ensures each course is delivered professionally.  May arrange for or contract with outside instructors/trainers as needed to assist with or improve the quality of course delivery.
d.    Solicits feedback from attendees or participants to measure the quality, effectiveness, and applicability of course content.  Makes modifications to course content or delivery methods as needed.
Course development.
a.     Participates in workshops and meetings for the development and maintenance of training materials.
b.    Develops course material either as a member of a team or individually.
c.     Through client contact proposes additional training subjects for development.
 " location="China" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Business Development Manager - Maritime and Offshore Services - China id="1500267" description="Description
  Business Development Manager - Maritime and Offshore Services (China)
  This individual is responsible for formulating and implementing business development strategies (including marketing and product development strategies) to help the assigned office and the Maritime and Offshore Service Line meet their strategic objectives. The position requires a self-directed individual who will define identify and realize opportunities to grow Maritime and offshore service line across China, within the principal duties and responsibilities under the direction of General Manager for China. (The successful candidate must be able to live and work in China without country restrictions.)
  Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
  The Business Development Manager will:
  Lead and drive the sales to the main clients in the various market sectors such as shipyard, offshore engineering, Gas, design Institute etc.
Develop, communicate, implement, and maintain plans for performing assigned business development activities (e.g. marketing material development, conference exhibits, etc.) providing appropriate coverage to all business lines.
Manage assigned business development activities within established budgets, gaining approval in advance from the Vice President and General Manager for any expenses beyond budget.
Perform special development/marketing projects (e.g. leading focus groups) as requested by Business Line Managers and/or the Vice President and General Manager.
Participate in regular Business Development Team meetings to provide updates on progress, communicate upcoming activities/events, and coordinate activities with other members of the Business Development Team.
Provide strategic insight into future business initiatives, market drivers, and competitor activities for inclusion in local and corporate business plans.
Develop business development skills (marketing, sales, presentation, etc.) amongst the office personnel, and jointly ensure that the staff has the materials/resources needed to effectively develop new business opportunities.
Identify business development program weaknesses to the Vice President and General Manager and propose appropriate/innovative solutions.
 " location="Taiwan-Taiwan Taipei" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Business Development Manager - Taiwan id="1500264" description="Description
  Business Development Manager – Taiwan
Description
  The Business Development Manager is responsible for generating sales and growth initiatives within a territory / region of ABS Consulting Inc. in Taiwan. This is a natural growth position for anybody seeking more senior roles in the Company.
  Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
  Main objective is to sell ABS Consulting services using the strength of local affiliate’s business structure.
Define and maintain target lists of prospect clients for accounts to be targeted in region. Client prospecting in target region.
Develop a sales strategy for region to achieve defined sales targets.
Provides sales forecast data as well as other market and customer information for use in sales planning.
Stays within expense budgets, and observe Company sales policies.
Produce local proposals for clients / prospects in accordance with ABS Consulting procedures and pricing guidelines and delegation of authority.
Actively follow up on all proposals and conduct client presentations where required. 
Provides support to operations as necessary to ensure customers are receiving appropriate service.
Assists in collections as necessary.
Communicates regularly, with   General Manager regarding opportunities, challenges and any other business matters.
Participates in special projects and teams as necessary to support the overall development of the business.
Meets or exceeds delegated sales targets.
Sell the broad spectrum of ABS Consulting services to Oil &amp; Gas, Power, Petrochemical and Maritime Industry.
Willing to spend at least 50% of the time meeting customers, and the rest in developing proposal, sales follow-up and sales pipeline development
 " location="Japan-Japan Yokohama-Yokohama" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Business Development Manager - Japan id="1500260" description="Description
 Business Development Manager – Japan
Description
  Responsible for developing and implementing sales plans and actions to increase revenues and profitability. Reports to VP of APAC region or any personnel nominated by him in work duties.
  Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
  Device and enact effective brand recognition and brand positioning strategies and serve as an enthusiastic evangelist for ABS Consulting;
Formulate and execute business plan for the Oil &amp; Gas services industry within Japan;
Coordinate technical, engineering, marketing, district, and other resources within ABS Consulting Services to assigned large projects. Lead the total sales effort on these assigned projects within budget constraints;
Responsible for driving growth within the key clients to produce significant business growth in the region;
Proactively develop competitive business development and sales strategies to ensure a continual flow of opportunities and maximum revenue growth for the region;
Establish and build strong, long lasting relationships with key oil &amp; gas customers;
Responsible for meeting yearly Budgeted Business Development Revenue targets;
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Nuclear and Radiological Risk Analyst id="1500237" description="Description
 The Nuclear and Radiological Risk Analyst will work on a dynamic team comprised of contract employees and highly engaged client representatives to meet fast-paced project requirements and provide end-user support. Analysts on the team provide risk analysis, game theory, model development, and associated support services on-site with the client in Washington DC. Members of the team are often provided the opportunity to influence ground breaking work in risk analysis, game theory and modelling.

Responsibilities:
• Review available data, translate information requests into analysis criteria based on available data, conduct analysis using MS Excel and proprietary analysis systems, and correctly interpret results
• Analyze datasets to generate descriptive statistics and perform statistical analysis to identify trends and anomalies in data
• Understand risk concepts including likelihood, probability, frequency, threat, vulnerability, and consequence for terrorism and non-terrorism events
• Conduct fault tree, event tree, and discrete event simulation analysis.
• Support subject matter experts, and become an SME in support of specific areas of risk modeling
• Possess basic to mid-level understanding of relational databases and database structures
• Perform research to support new/updated methodology and model development
• Develop briefing materials and write reports to communicate concepts and analysis results to client and end users
• Be able to translate business needs and gaps into requirements documentation and initial design concepts to support software development
• Be comfortable presenting your work to a small audience (10-20 people) conveying data results or facilitating discussion to support a client decision
• Maintain a positive working environment and can-do attitude to foster productive and healthy team and client relationships
• Alert supervisor to opportunities for new work and business development
• Support the development of proposals for new and existing work
 " location="United States of America-Texas-Houston" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Fall Intern 2015 id="1500259" description="Description
 ABS is looking for full-time students pursuing a BS, MS, or PhD degree in one of the following engineering disciplines:  Civil, Electrical, Mechanical, Marine, Structural, Ocean, or Naval Architecture. 
  Applicants must be working towards an engineering degree at an accredited school and have completed 50 semester hours before the start of the internship. 
  Applicants will be placed in our Corporate office in Houston, TX.
  Internship responsibilities include, but are not limited to engineering plan review, technical plan review, research, analysis, performing calculations, database maintenance, and testing engineering software. 
  Some of the departments that could utilize your skills include: 
Corporate Technology
Research &amp; Product Development
Operational Safety &amp; Evaluation
 " location="United States of America-Texas-Houston" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Rotational Engineer- July 2016 id="1500224" description="Description
 Rotational Program

Imagine yourself working for a company where innovation, teamwork, and customer service comprise the core of that organization—a place where talented people from over 70 countries work together to set standards of excellence in the maritime world. Sound exciting? Then ABS is the right place for you!

ABS currently has openings for its full-time rotational program. This program launches twice a year in January and July. This program offers recent university graduates the opportunity to accelerate their career growth through a structured framework that combines challenging work rotations combined with technical and professional training for a period of up to 14 months. The goal of the rotational program is to develop our next generation of ABS professionals.

The rotational program provides both on the job experience and classroom development.

Qualifications:

The rotational program is highly selective, and space is limited. To be considered, candidates must have:

• Degree in an engineering related field
• An interest in exploring multifunctional assignments with our 3 core business’, Engineering, Technology, and Survey
• Demonstrated leadership ability
• Ability to interface with customers which requires good communication skills
• Academic achievement as demonstrated by an overall GPA of 3.0 or higher
 " location="United States of America-Texas-Houston" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Rotational Engineer- January 2016 id="1500204" description="Description
 Rotational Program

Imagine yourself working for a company where innovation, teamwork, and customer service comprise the core of that organization—a place where talented people from over 70 countries work together to set standards of excellence in the maritime world. Sound exciting? Then ABS is the right place for you!

ABS currently has openings for its full-time rotational program. This program launches twice a year in January and July. This program offers recent university graduates the opportunity to accelerate their career growth through a structured framework that combines challenging work rotations combined with technical and professional training for a period of up to 14 months. The goal of the rotational program is to develop our next generation of ABS professionals.

The rotational program provides both on the job experience and classroom development.

Qualifications:

The rotational program is highly selective, and space is limited. To be considered, candidates must have:

• Degree in an engineering related field
• An interest in exploring multifunctional assignments with our 3 core business’, Engineering, Technology, and Survey
• Demonstrated leadership ability
• Ability to interface with customers which requires good communication skills
• Academic achievement as demonstrated by an overall GPA of 3.0 or higher
 " location="United Kingdom-Cheshire-Warrington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Accounts Payable Clerk id="1500255" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is an International company which specializes in the certification and classification of ships and offshore structures.
  It is expanding its Finance function in Warrington to create a UK Shared Service Centre and looking for Accounts Payable Clerks to join the new function.
  Principle duties and responsibilities

The Europe division AP function is a multi currency operation covering around 40 countries across the EMEA region.
1.       Process invoice details and invoice scanned prints onto the system
2.       Review coding of submitted invoices
3.       Manage cash files from outlying foreign offices, processing the payments through the Oracle invoicing and payment modules
4.       Prepare and distribute foreign payments
5.       Assist with reconciliation of some GL balance sheet accounts
6.       Ensure clearing accounts are reconciled at month end
7.       Reconcile the payment related bank accounts
8.       Ensure AP trial balance is tidied up on a regular basis
9.       Deal with AP payment queries from internal and external parties in an efficient and effective way
10.   Carry out account analysis and investigation as required
11.   Maintain an effective filing system
12.   Be prepared to undertake, with support, some Accounts Assistant duties if required.
13.   Close the monthly AP accounting periods
 " location="United Kingdom-Cheshire-Warrington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Accounts Payable Supervisor id="1500256" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is an International company which specializes in the certification and classification of ships and offshore structures.
 It is expanding its Finance function in Warrington to create a UK Shared Service Centre and looking for an Accounts Payable Supervisor to join the new function.
General Summary
 Responsible for the day-to-day supervision of the Accounts Payable functions for assigned Division.  Accountable for the accuracy of Accounts Payable information both entered and retrieved from our accounting system.  This position requires a minimum of six (6) years progressively responsible Accounts Payable experience.
 Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
 I.                    Maintains the Accounts Payable records.
II.                  Supervises Accounts Payable functions.
III.                Reviews Accounts Payable system processes and suggests improvements to management.
IV.                Performs various accounting duties, such as the preparation of journal entries, the analysis of various general ledger accounts, reviewing incoming data from subsidiaries and works with field offices regarding accounting issues.
V.                  Participates in the cash management program.
VI.                Prepares required statutory filings of local government entities as may be required.
 " location="United Kingdom-Cheshire-Warrington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Accounts Receivable Clerk id="1500257" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is an International company which specializes in the certification and classification of ships and offshore structures.
 It is expanding its Finance function in Warrington to create a UK Shared Service Centre and looking for Accounts Receivable Clerks to join the new function.
General Summary:
You will be part of a team of 4 A/R Clerks working within a busy Accounts Receivables Department of a Financial Services Group reporting to the A/R Supervisor.

Daily tasks
·         Downloading of bank statements
·         Booking of Receipts
·         Raising of Intercompany Collection advices to other Countries within the Group where necessary
·         Chasing up remittance advice/allocation details where necessary
·         Processing write offs to bank charges/foreign exchange differences
·         Obtain authorization for refunds from Regional ABS offices and pass to supervisor for processing
·         Liaise with Regional Offices/Clients to resolve allocation queries

Weekly
·         Running of A/R interfaces from Subledger to General Ledger for the Countries under your responsibility
·         Follow up with Regional Offices/Clients re: outstanding queries

Monthly
·         Running of Aged Debtors Reports for all Countries under your responsibility
·         Running of Detailed Trial Balance Reports for all Countries under your responsibility
·         Check balances in Trades Receipts account in A/R &amp; G/L match
·         Prepare Bank Reconciliations for all Countries under your responsibility

General
·         Other Ad hoc duties as required including, filing archiving, scanning photocopying. Cover for other team members when on holiday/sick including raising intercompany recharge invoices, processing write offs, refunds to clients, setting up bank accounts
 " location="United Kingdom-Cheshire-Warrington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Accounts Receivable Supervisor id="1500258" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is an International company which specializes in the certification and classification of ships and offshore structures.
 It is expanding its Finance function in Warrington to create a UK Shared Service Centre and looking for an Accounts Receivable Supervisor to join the new function.
General Summary
 Responsible for the day-to-day supervision of the Accounts Receivable functions.  Accountable for the accuracy of Accounts Receivable information both entered and retrieved from accounting system.  This position requires a minimum of six (6) years progressively responsible Accounts Receivable experience.
 Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
 I.                    Reviews journal entries/cash application prepared by accounts receivable staff.
II.                  Reviews and approves reconciliations.
III.                Runs a preliminary aging report to correct all unallocated items and identify collections received for which an invoice was not posted.
IV.                Runs final aging reports for distribution to cost centers.
V.                  Supports Manager in the handling of all telephone correspondence with clients and branches regarding questions on statements or account balances.
VI.                Reports daily cash position and weekly forecast and monthly cash analysis actuals.
VII.              Assists, coaches, trains or mentors AR Team.
VIII.            Processes daily detail for bank balances and prior day detail.
IX.                Processes Credit Card payments.
X.                  Performs other duties and participates in special projects as assigned.
 " location="Cameroon-Cameroon Douala-Douala" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Surveyor - Cameroon id="1500235" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is an International company which specializes in the certification and classification of ships and offshore structures.

It is expanding its operations in Africa and seeking to employ a Surveyor in Cameroon. If you are looking for your next challenge, this is the opportunity for you!

General Summary
This position will be a 2 year assignment and is an excellent opportunity to join the West Africa team in the fastest developing offshore market in the world.

This Survey position would be suitable for candidates with Five (5) plus years’ experience in the Marine industry. The position will give the selected candidate a 6/2 rotation and an opportunity to travel throughout Africa covering commercial shipping and offshore related Survey work.
 " location="United States of America-South Carolina-Charleston" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Training and Exercise Specialist id="1500244" description="Description
 Training and Exercise Specialist

General Experience: 
Successful candidate shall have approximately 1-3 years of relevant professional experience (experience in the development and conduct of Homeland Security Exercise and Evaluation Program-compliant exercises preferred). 
The Candidate will serve as an Exercise Support Team member and be responsible for completing logistical and administrative tasks. These tasks include, but are not limited to: participant outreach and tracking; event planning and coordination; and development of materials and project documentation.
These tasks include, but are not limited to: participant outreach and tracking; event planning and coordination; and development of exercise materials and project documentation.
 " location="United Kingdom-Cheshire-Warrington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Business Development Manager - Warrington id="1500128" description="Description
  General Summary
The American Bureau of Shipping is a global organization that covers to main areas classification services to the maritime world and consulting services not limited to the shipping industry. This particular opportunity sits within the consulting branch under the QE team.  The QE team focuses on the certifications of management systems inclusive of:
 
·         Environmental, Health and Safety / ISO 14001 OHSAS 18001.
·         Security/ISO 28000
·         Information Security/ISO 27001
·         Quality/ISO 9001, ISO 20000, ISO 29000
·         Social Accountability/SA 8000, BSCI, SMETA
·         Energy /ISO 50001
·         Automotive /ISO/TS 16949
·         Aerospace / AS 9100

  The QE team is looking for a Business Development Manager (BDM), someone that will generate leads, bring and maintain business. As we are a small team the BDM is expected to roll up their sleeves and get involved in all phases of business development.  This includes researching potential clients, generating leads, developing intelligence/market insight as part of proposals to potential and current clients. The follow up and nurture of these client relationships is key to our business. Whilst we have greater focus in UK, and we are looking to grow specifically in UK.
Principle Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
1.       Research and generate market leads for potential clients and work.
2.       Handle proposal development documents and activities (simple and complex) including screening client information for scope determination, proposal generation and timely submittal of quote to the client.
3.       Day to day contact with potential and existing clients for new sales, quoting and contracting activities.
4.       Receipt and review of all applications and required contracting information. 
5.       Review contracts assuring the requirements are clearly defined in line with clear expectations and services provided by ABS QE.
6.       Maintain database.
7.       Generate sales reports.
8.       Administer corporate master agreements
 " location="Germany-Germany Hamburg-Hamburg" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Business Development Manager - Hamburg id="1500243" description="Description
  General Summary
The American Bureau of Shipping is a global organization that covers to main areas classification services to the maritime world and consulting services not limited to the shipping industry. This particular opportunity sits within the consulting branch under the QE team.  The QE team focuses on the certifications of management systems inclusive of:
 
·         Environmental, Health and Safety / ISO 14001 OHSAS 18001.
·         Security/ISO 28000
·         Information Security/ISO 27001
·         Quality/ISO 9001, ISO 20000, ISO 29000
·         Social Accountability/SA 8000, BSCI, SMETA
·         Energy /ISO 50001
·         Automotive /ISO/TS 16949
·         Aerospace / AS 9100

  The QE team is looking for a Business Development Manager (BDM), someone that will generate leads, bring and maintain business. As we are a small team the BDM is expected to roll up their sleeves and get involved in all phases of business development.  This includes researching potential clients, generating leads, developing intelligence/market insight as part of proposals to potential and current clients. The follow up and nurture of these client relationships is key to our business. Whilst we have greater focus in Germany, and we are looking to grow specifically in Germany.
Principle Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
1.       Research and generate market leads for potential clients and work.
2.       Handle proposal development documents and activities (simple and complex) including screening client information for scope determination, proposal generation and timely submittal of quote to the client.
3.       Day to day contact with potential and existing clients for new sales, quoting and contracting activities.
4.       Receipt and review of all applications and required contracting information. 
5.       Review contracts assuring the requirements are clearly defined in line with clear expectations and services provided by ABS QE.
6.       Maintain database.
7.       Generate sales reports.
8.       Administer corporate master agreements
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Senior Risk Engineer id="1500212" description="Description
 Summary:
The Analyst will work closely on a dynamic team comprised of ABS Consulting employees and highly engaged client representatives to meet fast-paced project requirements and provide end-user support. Analysts on the team provide risk analysis, risk communication, model development, and associated support services on-site with the client in Washington DC. Members of the team are often provided with increased responsibility in a short time and with the opportunity to influence ground breaking work in risk analysis.

Responsibilities include:
• Working in a team environment with daily coordination of activities
• Understand risk concepts including likelihood, probability, frequency, threat, vulnerability, and consequence for terrorism and non-terrorism events
• Support subject matter experts, and/or become an SME in support of specific areas of risk modeling
• Perform research to support new/updated methodology and model development
• Develop briefing materials and write reports to communicate concepts and analysis results to clients
• Be able to translate business needs and gaps into requirements documentation and initial design concepts
• Conduct analysis using MS Access and/or Excel
• Analyze datasets to generate descriptive statistics and perform statistical analysis to identify trends and anomalies in data
• Be comfortable presenting your work to an audience of 10-20 people conveying data results or facilitating discussion to support a client decision
• Alert supervisor to opportunities for new work and business development
• Support the development of proposals for new and existing work
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Analyst, Risk (Location Washington DC) id="1500153" description="Description
 Summary:
The Analyst will work closely on a dynamic team comprised of ABS Consulting employees and highly engaged client representatives to meet fast-paced project requirements and provide end-user support.  Analysts on the team provide risk analysis, risk communication, model development, and associated support services on-site with the client in Washington DC.  Members of the team are often provided with increased responsibility in a short time and with the opportunity to influence ground breaking work in risk analysis.

Responsibilities include:
Review available data, translate information requests into analysis criteria based on available data, conduct analysis using MS Access and/or Excel, and correctly interpret results
Analyze datasets to generate descriptive statistics and perform statistical analysis to identify trends and anomalies in data
Understand risk concepts including likelihood, probability, frequency, threat, vulnerability, and consequence for terrorism and non-terrorism events
Support subject matter experts, and/or become an SME in support of specific areas of risk modeling
Provide hands-on assistance and trouble-shooting support to field users of modeling tools
Possess basic to mid-level understanding of relational databases and database structures
Perform research to support new/updated methodology and model development
Develop briefing materials and write reports to communicate concepts and analysis results to client and end users
Be able to translate business needs and gaps into requirements documentation and initial design concepts to support software development
Be comfortable presenting your work to a small audience (10-20 people) conveying data results or facilitating discussion to support a client decision
Alert supervisor to opportunities for new work and business development
Support the development of proposals for new and existing work

 " location="Norway-Norway Stavanger-Stavanger" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Electrical / Electronic Engineer id="1500001" description="Description
 ABS is currently looking for an Electrical/Electronic Engineer to join the Stavanger office on a permanent basis. This position requires someone from a Marine Background who is looking for their next challenge.
  This role will have a reporting line into our London Engineering department and will require travel to London and other European locations including inside Norway.
  General Summary:

This is an engineering position for engineers with 5+ years related industry experience. The position performs engineer design review and analysis assignments normally involving a major project or several smaller or less complex projects. These projects by nature of their complexity and difficulty require the fully competent application of conventional knowledge in a particular field of engineering or science. Through broader and more technically challenging work assignments, you will develop a thorough understanding of policies, methods and procedures.
Work will involve but not be limited to:
·                    Appraisals of Electrical Documentation and Drawings to assess safety and suitability for systems in the Marine Environment
·                     Low Voltage work and Heavy Electrics up to 15KV+
·                     Propulsion Control and Dynamic Positioning
 " location="United States of America-Virginia-Arlington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Junior Risk Analyst id="1500191" description="Description
 Summary:
The Analyst will work closely on a dynamic team comprised of ABS Consulting employees and highly engaged client representatives to meet fast-paced project requirements and provide end-user support. Analysts on the team provide risk analysis, risk communication, model development, and associated support services on-site with the client in Washington DC. Members of the team are often provided with increased responsibility in a short time and with the opportunity to influence ground breaking work in risk analysis.

Responsibilities include:

Review available data, translate information requests into analysis criteria based on available data, conduct analysis using MS Access and/or Excel, and correctly interpret results
Analyze datasets to generate descriptive statistics and perform statistical analysis to identify trends and anomalies in data
Understand risk concepts including likelihood, probability, frequency, threat, vulnerability, and consequence for terrorism and non-terrorism events
Support subject matter experts, and/or become an SME in support of specific areas of risk modeling
Provide hands-on assistance and trouble-shooting support to field users of modeling tools
Possess basic to mid-level understanding of relational databases and database structures
Perform research to support new/updated methodology and model development
Develop briefing materials and write reports to communicate concepts and analysis results to client and end users
Be able to translate business needs and gaps into requirements documentation and initial design concepts to support software development
Be comfortable presenting your work to a small audience (10-20 people) conveying data results or facilitating discussion to support a client decision
Alert supervisor to opportunities for new work and business development
Support the development of proposals for new and existing work
 " location="United Kingdom-United Kingdom London-London" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Electrical/Electronic Engineer id="1500163" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is an International company which specializes in the certification and classification of ships and offshore structures.
It is expanding its operations in Africa and seeking to employ Surveyors in Angola.
Angola is seen by ABS as a high profile oil and gas region, and we provide a range of Classification Services toward the Shipping and Offshore Industries. As such we are looking to develop local talent who are able and willing to be part of the long term future of ABS in this country. If you are looking for your next challenge, this is the opportunity for you!
The position on offer is challenging, and ideally suited to graduate engineers, within a marine related discipline, who show a willingness to learn, and have a positive attitude toward working in a global organisation with a reputation for excellence and quality.
We will also consider candidates with specific marine / classification experience. ( e.g. Qualified Chief Engineers)

General Summary
These Survey positions are suitable for candidates with Five (5) plus years’ experience in the Marine industry. The position will give the selected candidate an opportunity to cultivate a thorough understanding of field operations, policies, methods and procedures and develop a career with ABS.
Typical Classification Surveyor duties include:
- Plan Hull and Machinery surveys in co-operation with our customers
- Execute surveys, and assist customers   within the boundary of the relevant ABS Rules and Statutory Regulations.
- Provide technical advice to our customers
- Reporting in accordance with global ABS Standards and Statutory requirements.
 " location="Angola-Angola Luanda-Luanda" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Surveyor - Angola id="1500148" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is an International company which specializes in the certification and classification of ships and offshore structures.
It is expanding its operations in Africa and seeking to employ Surveyors in Angola.
Angola is seen by ABS as a high profile oil and gas region, and we provide a range of Classification Services toward the Shipping and Offshore Industries. As such we are looking to develop local talent who are able and willing to be part of the long term future of ABS in this country. If you are looking for your next challenge, this is the opportunity for you!
The position on offer is challenging, and ideally suited to graduate engineers, within a marine related discipline, who show a willingness to learn, and have a positive attitude toward working in a global organisation with a reputation for excellence and quality.
We will also consider candidates with specific marine / classification experience. ( e.g. Qualified Chief Engineers)

General Summary
These Survey positions are suitable for candidates with Five (5) plus years’ experience in the Marine industry. The position will give the selected candidate an opportunity to cultivate a thorough understanding of field operations, policies, methods and procedures and develop a career with ABS.
Typical Classification Surveyor duties include:
- Plan Hull and Machinery surveys in co-operation with our customers
- Execute surveys, and assist customers   within the boundary of the relevant ABS Rules and Statutory Regulations.
- Provide technical advice to our customers
- Reporting in accordance with global ABS Standards and Statutory requirements.
 " location="Germany-Germany Hamburg-Hamburg" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Surveyor - Hamburg id="1500166" description="Description
 An entry level position for candidates with less than five (5) years experience in a comparable marine industry; or individuals with a minimum of three (3) years experience as an ABS Surveyor I.
Primary function is to examine and report on vessels and other marine structures during and after construction relative to compliance with the applicable requirements for maintaining the vessel in Classification with ABS, and meeting associated statutory and special service requirements related to Safety of Life at Sea, Loadline, Tonnage, Cargo Gear, and Pollution Prevention certification. Develops skills necessary for the administration of office procedures and monitoring of business performance at an assigned port.
This may be an intermediate level position for an individual under the supervision and guidance of experienced field surveyors.  Through broader and more technically challenging work assignments, individual will develop a thorough understanding of field operations, policies, methods, and procedures.

Principal Duties and Responsibilities
With the assistance and guidance of a more experienced senior level field surveyor:
·         Visits vessels, marine structures, and manufacturers for routine survey activities.
·         Performs work that involves conventional surveying practices, but may include moderately complex problem resolution and coordination of activities among other disciplines.
·         Prepares technically accurate and timely survey reports, and responses to letters, faxes, and other forms of communication.
·         Begins to work directly with clients to identify and resolve problems in area of technical expertise.
·         Maintains files in an orderly and up-to-date manner.
 " location="United States of America-Maryland-Rockville" schedule="Full-time" />
  <VB. NET Programmer id="1500143" description="Description
 General Summary

Under the direction of the Director of Consequence Modeling, this position will support the activities of Safety, Risk and Compliance. 

Principal Duties and Responsibilities (PDR)
Working with clients to specify changes to be made in existing code packages to meet new client requirements.
Making changes in existing code written in Visual Basic and/or Fortran to support client needs.
Convert existing code from Visual Basic to VB.Net to support the next generation of code
Document code changes
Construct test plans and testing new code 
Conduct independent check calculations to verify code results
Develop project design documents.
 " location="United Kingdom-United Kingdom London-London" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Senior Mechanical Engineer id="1500157" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping is an International company which specializes in the certification and classification of ships and offshore structures.
Are you an experienced Mechanical Engineer from a Marine Engine Design or Development background and looking for your next challenge? If so, this is the opportunity for you!

General Summary
This role will involve the development of existing and new class requirements for internal combustion engines, emission control equipment and alternative fuel related technologies. This would include rules, guides, advisories and associated internal process instructions and briefing notes. This role may include the presentation and promotion of these products both internally and externally to ABS.
The position will require travel within our Europe Division to meet with clients and support other ABS departments. The ideal candidate will also be happy to participate in relevant industry committee and standard development activities such as IMO, IACS, ISO, CIMAC etc.
 " location="United Kingdom-Cheshire-Warrington" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Source, Third Party and Expediting Inspectors id="1401340" description="Description
 ABS Group is looking to expand its European network of Source, Third Party and Expediting Inspectors.  Our European inspection services are managed from the ABS Group office in Warrington, UK.  The key function of this service team is to provide inspecting services to a global portfolio of clients in the oil and gas, industrial, nuclear, renewable, power generation and transportation sectors.
We are looking to broaden our coverage and deepen our pool of resources across a wide range of skills across Europe and are seeking suitably skilled resources to utilise on an ad-hoc, sub-contract basis.

The successful candidates are expected to be familiar with typical inspection and testing requirements including:

Documentation Reviews
Mechanical Testing
Non-destructive Testing
Visual Examination
Hydrostatic Testing
Material Selection
Dimensional Inspection
Welding Procedures
Functional Testing
Coating Inspections
Practical application of specification e.g. ASME, API, ASTM, BS etc
FATs and SITs

Job Responsibilities:
·         Perform third party inspection and other inspection duties as requested by the company. 
·         Attend the client’s facility, as scheduled, in a timely fashion. 
·         Receipt and review of Inspection Test Plan, Manufacturing procedure specification &amp; quality plan
·         Review and examination of design, procurement, fabrication, construction and commissioning documentation, records and activities. 
·         Witness and monitor suppliers work activities, inspection and test in accordance with the approved Quality Plan, ITP, Quality Procedures
·         Ensure suppliers have relevant, up to date codes, standards, specifications and drawings.
·         Review original material certificate for compliances to codes and specifications.
·         Ensure testing, measuring, welding, NDE equipment is fully calibrated per specification and has current certification.
·         Reporting non-compliance and poor performance to client without fail
Prepare and submit inspection reports/release notes etc as required in a timely manner.

 " location="United States of America-Louisiana-Harahan" schedule="Full-time" />
  <Engineer II id="1500117" description="Description
 American Bureau of Shipping (ABS) is seeking Engineers II to:
  Responsible for the compliance of the structural analysis of ship designs with ABS Rules and other applicable Industry standards. Provide structural classification services for commercial vessels less than 90 meters long, ranging from Offshore Support Vessels to Towing Vessels, Barges, River Vessels and High Speed Crafts. Conduct analysis of ship scantlings, section modulus, and deck layouts and schematics. Perform necessary calculations using both knowledge of company software and the ability to perform hand calculations as well. Interface extensively with ABS Surveyors as well as engineers outside the work group and external clients. Use conventional engineering practices such as complex problem resolution of conflicting design requirements and coordination of activities among other disciplines to complete assigned projects. Draft technical correspondence and other forms of communication for internal as well as external distribution.
 " location="Angola-Angola Luanda-Luanda" schedule="Full-time" />
</opt>
